Same Planet. Different World.
Journey to the Center of the Earth is a action, science
fiction, adventure film directed by Eric Brevig.
On a quest to find out what happened to his missing brother, a scientist, his nephew and their
mountain guide discover a fantastic and dangerous lost world in the center of the earth.
Trevor Anderson, played by Brendan Fraser.
Sean Anderson, played by Josh Hutcherson.
Hannah Ásgeirsson, played by Anita Briem.
Professor Alan Kitzens, played by Seth Meyers.
Max Anderson, played by Jean Michel Paré.
Elizabeth Anderson, played by Jane Wheeler.
Journey to the Center of the Earth is a 2008 American 3D science fantasy action-adventure film
starring Brendan Fraser in the main role, alongside Josh Hutcherson and Anita Briem.
Directed by Eric Brevig, it is an adaptation of Jules Verne's 1864 novel
in which the novel exists within the film's universe.
The film tells the story of a volcanologist and his nephew who embark on a mission to go look for the former's
missing brother with help from an Icelandic guide as they come across the center of the Earth.
Journey to the Center of the Earth was released
on July 11, 2008, by Warner Bros.
It received mixed reviews from critics, and earned
$244.2 million against a $60 million budget.
The film also introduced the 4DX movie format, featuring "4D" motion effects in a specially designed cinema in Seoul, South Korea, using tilting seats and other
effects to convey motion, wind, sprays of water and sharp air, probe lights to mimic lightning, fog, scents, and other theatrical special effects.
A sequel, Journey 2: The Mysterious Island, was released on
February 10, 2012, with only Hutcherson returning.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, volcano,
iceland, prehistory, prehistoric creature.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.